>> FROM THE HEART OF WHERE
INNOVATION, MONEY, AND POWER
CLYDE IN SILICON VALLEY AND
BEYOND, THIS IS "BLOOMBERG
TECHNOLOGY"
WITH CAROLINE HYDE AND ED
LUDLOW.
CAROLINE:
LIVE FROM NEW YORK AND SAN
FRANCISCO, THIS IS "BLOOMBERG
TECHNOLOGY."
INTEL IS WORKING ON A PLAN B.
THE BLOOMBERG EXCLUSIVE ON
BANKERS EYEING A POTENTIAL SALE
OF THE FOUNDRY DIVISION AND
MORE COST CUTS. ED:
ELON MUSK'S BATTLE WITH BRAZIL
DEEPENS, THREATENING SOCIAL
PLATFORM X AND SPACEX'S
STARLINK BUSINESS. CAROLINE:
TECH FIGHTS TO END THE WEEK
STRONG.
WE HAVE A KEY CIO ON THE SHOW.
LET'S JUST DWELL ON THESE
MARKETS FOR A MOMENT.
WE END THE MONTH AS WE STARTED
IT, ON THE DOWNSIDE.
WE HAD A BRUTAL SYLLABUS ON
AUGUST, AND -- BRUTAL SELL OFF
TO START AUGUST. WE ARE TRYING
TO MAKE SOME POWER HIGHER ON
THIS FRIDAY, AND WE HAVE
CERTAIN THINGS TO THANK FOR
THAT.
MORE BROADLY THIS IS A WEEK WE
ARE FIXATED ON ONE NAME ALONE,
NVIDIA.
HE DID NOT LIVE UP TO SOME OF
THE HYPO.
ED, WHAT ARE YOU WATCHING ON
THE MICRO DATA? ED:
YOU CAN NEVER QUITE GET THE
NEWS FLOW.
INTEL IS UP AT THIS POINT THE
MOST SINCE OCTOBER 2023.
THE MOST SINCE OCTOBER OR LATE
2022.
THERE IS A DETAILED NOTE FROM
BLOOMBERG ABOUT BASICALLY PLAN
B. CLEARLY THE STREET LIKES IT.
CAROLINE:
IT'S BLOOMBERG EXCLUSIVE
REPORTING, LEARNING THAT INTEL
IS LOOKING TO INVESTMENT
BANKERS FOR HELP NAVIGATING THE
MOST DIFFICULT PERIOD IN ITS
56-YEAR HISTORY.
THE CHIPMAKER IS DISCUSSING A
RANGE OF SCENARIOS INCLUDING A
SPLIT OF ITS PRODUCT DESIGN AND
MANUFACTURING BUSINESSES.
IAN KING IS THE MAN HELPING
DRIVE THE EXCLUSIVE REPORTING.
MAYBE THIS SHOULD COME AS NO
SURPRISE, BUT IT IS QUITE
WHOLESALE LOOK AT THE BUSINESS.
>> AFTER THEIR EARNINGS
ANNOUNCEMENT, THERE'S CLEARLY
BEEN A LOT OF PRESSURE ON THE
COMPANY, AND CLEARLY PEOPLE ARE
LOOKING AT THIS COMPANY AND
SAYING CAN YOU DO WHAT IT SET
OUT TO DO.
IT'S KIND OF NATURAL THE
MANAGEMENT AND THE BOARD WOULD
DO THEIR JOB, AND THAT IS TO
LOOK AT THEIR OPTIONS, REALLY.
NOTHING IS BEING DECIDED AND
EVERYTHING IS IN THIS
PRELIMINARY STAGES.
AS THE MARKET IS SHOWING US
TODAY, THIS IS KIND OF A
HEALTHY AND NATURAL THING FOR A
COMPANY IN THIS KIND OF
SITUATION TO BE DOING. ED:
WE CALLED IT PLAN B, BUT IT
MIGHT AS WELL BE PLAN C, D, E.
THINGS HAVE BEEN DIFFICULT FOR
INTEL.
WE USE THE WORD "CHIPMAKER"
A LOT FOR ALL KINDS OF SEMI-
CONDUCTOR COMPANIES, BUT IN
INTEL'S CASE IT IS TRUE.
THE DESIGN CHIPS AND THEN THEY
MANUFACTURE THEM FOR THEMSELVES.
THE PROBLEM THEY HAVE GOT IS
THAT THEY DON'T CURRENTLY
MANUFACTURE CHIPS FOR ANYONE
ELSE.
THAT IS THE FINANCIAL ISSUE.
IAN: IT IS A CONUNDRUM.
THEY ARE SAYING, LOOK, WE WANT
TO BE A FOUNDRY.
IN ORDER TO DO THAT, WE NEED
MORE FACTORIES, WE NEED WHAT
TECHNOLOGY.
BUT THAT COSTS A LOT OF MONEY.
THE MONEY COMES FROM THE
PRODUCTS THEY SELL.
THE AMOUNT OF PRODUCT THEY ARE
SELLING IS GOING DOWN OR NOT
BEING AS LUCRATIVE AS THEY USED
TO BE.
IT IS A DIFFICULT SITUATION.
THE ARGUMENT HAS BEEN FOR SOME
TIME NOW THAT PERHAPS THESE TWO
DIVISIONS ARE BETTER OFF
SEPARATE, AND THAT WAY IT IS
GOING TO BE EASY TO ATTRACT
OUTSIDE CUSTOMERS. CAROLINE:
THE KEY ISSUES THAT PAT
GELSINGER CAME ON -- THIS WAS
KIND OF HIS FOCUS.
I WANT TO GO BACK TO WHAT HE
WAS TELLING THE MARKET, THE
INVESTOR BASE.
TAKE A LISTEN, IAN.
>> WE DELIVERED A SOLID Q1.
WE MET ON REVENUE, WE BEAT ON
EARNINGS.
A BIT TEPID IN THE FIRST HALF,
BUT WE SEE A LOT OF IMPROVEMENT
AS WE GO THROUGH THE YEAR.
WITH THAT, OBVIOUSLY THE
FOUNDRY BUSINESS -- WE ARE
GOING TO SEE PROGRESS ON THE
FOUNDRY BUSINESS EVERY QUARTER
FROM NOW UNTIL THE END OF THE
DECADE. CAROLINE:
MAYBE NOT TO THE END OF THE
DECADE.
HOW MUCH OF AN IMPACT IS THIS
ON PAT GELSINGER IN AND OF
HIMSELF, IAN? IAN:
HE CAME -- HE WAS BROUGHT INTO
TURN THIS COMPANY AROUND, IF
YOU LIKE, TO MAKE UP FOR THE
MISTAKES OF HIS PREDECESSORS.
THE PROBLEM IS THAT IT TAKES
TIME.
YOU DON'T DESIGN A CHIP ONE DAY
AND HAVE IT ON THE MARKET THE
NEXT.
WE ARE LOOKING AT YEARS TO HAVE
NEW PRODUCTS OUT THERE AND GAIN
TRACTION.
IN SNC IS DOING WHAT HE SAID HE
WAS GOING TO DO -- IN A SENSE
HE IS DOING WHAT HE SAID HE WAS
GOING TO DO.
AT THE TIME INVESTORS SIGN OFF
ON THAT.
THE PROBLEM IS WE ARE LOOKING
AT THE BOTTOM, THE POINT AT
WHICH THINGS START TO GET
BETTER.
THE PROBLEM PAT HAS IS A LOT OF
THINGS HAVE COME TOGETHER AND
THAT HASN'T HAPPENED YET.
DON'T HAVE A SIGN WE ARE BACK
ON THE UPSLOPE. ED:
IAN KING, THANK YOU FOR THIS
ENTIRE WEEK, NVIDIA EARNINGS,
THE REPORTING.
IT'S BEEN QUITE A WEEK IN THE
WORLD OF SEMICONDUCTORS.
IT'S BEEN A BIG WEEK IN
MARKETS, PARTICULARLY FOR
TECHNOLOGY INVESTORS.
UNDERSTATEMENT.
THE FOCUS, AND VIDEOS EARNINGS
WHICH -- NVIDIA'S EARNINGS
WHICH WERE JUST NOT ENOUGH
AGAINST SKYHIGH EXPECTATIONS.
TAKE EARNINGS AT LARGE ARE ALL
UNDER DESK, TOO.
JOINING US AS THE CHIEF
INVESTMENT OFFICER OF THE MEDIC
INNOVATION EQUITIES AT
ALLIANCEBERNSTEIN.
THAT IS WHERE WE START.
DO WE KNOW MORE ABOUT THE WORLD
OF TECHNOLOGY, PARTICULARLY THE
LONGEVITY OF THIS AI INVESTMENT
CYCLE, THAN WE DID PRIOR TO
NVIDIA'S EARNINGS A FEW DAYS
AGO?
>> WELL, THANK YOU FOR HAVING
ME HERE.
SO TO START, ONE, DEMAND FOR
MEANS VERY STRONG.
WE ARE AT THE VERY EARLY STAGES.
WHEN WE SAY DEMAND IS STRONG,
WE ARE SEEING IT FROM
ENTERPRISES AND WE ARE SEEING
IT FROM NATIONS AS WELL.
AT THIS STAGE AND WITH NEW
PRODUCT COMING, YOU CONTINUE TO
SEE VERY ROBUST DEMAND FOR
EXISTING PRODUCT.
THAT IS SOMETHING WE HAVE NEVER
SEEN BEFORE IN PREVIOUS PRODUCT
CYCLES. THAT IS A STRONG SIGNAL.
TWO, WHEN WE SAY "EARLY STAGES,"
YES, IT IS EARLY STAGES ON THE
SUPPLY SIDE.
WE HAVE GONE FOR MANUFACTURING
A SINGLE CHIP TO SYSTEM-LEVEL
COMPUTE.
A LOT OF THINGS HAVE BECOME
TOGETHER, WHETHER IT BE MEMORY,
NETWORKING, SOFTWARE, OR THE
INFRASTRUCTURE SIDE.
A LOT HAS TO COME TOGETHER, AND
ECOSYSTEM ITSELF HAS TO ADAPT.
THERE WILL BE UNEVENNESS FROM
TIME TO TIME.
GO BACK TO A DEMAND-SUPPLY
IMBALANCE, BUT WE REMAIN VERY
CONSTRUCTIVE ON THE OUTLOOK OF
AI. ED:
LEI, ALLIANCEBERNSTEIN, BASED
ON BLOOMBERG'S DATA, IS THE
22ND LARGEST SHAREHOLDER OF
NVIDIA.
JUST GENERALLY YOUR REACTION TO
THE EARNINGS STATEMENT CALL AND
THE WHOLE WATCH PARTY HAPPENING
FOR THAT NAME AROUND THE WORLD?
LEI:
WE BELIEVE THAT NVIDIA REMAIN
WHEN THE LEADING PLAYERS TO
REMAIN ONE OF THE LEADING
PLAYERS IN THE AI ECOSYSTEM.
WHAT THEY ARE DOING IS TENSE
FORMATIVE, AND IT IS REALLY.
THAT'S WHAT THEY ARE DOING IS
TRANSFORMATIVE, AND IT IS --
WHAT THEY ARE DOING IS
TRANSFORMATIVE, AND IT IS EARLY.
SOMETIMES YOU HAVE TO LOOK OUT
TO EVEN MAKE MONEY NEAR-TERM OR
LONG-TERM. WE CONTINUE TO HAVE A
CONSTRUCTIVE HAVE YOU OF THE AI
ECOSYSTEM AS A WHOLE, AND WE
BELIEVE IN NVIDIA'S LEADING
POSITION AS WELL. CAROLINE:
LEI, I CAN ONLY IMAGINE HOW
OFTEN AT OCONTO -- A CARTEL
PARTY OR DINNER PARTY YOU'RE
TAKEN TO ONE SIDE AND ROLLED
OVER THE RETURN DESK GRILLED ON
-- GRILLED ON THE RETURN ON
GENERATIVE AI A LOT OF PEOPLE
ARE WONDERING WHEN GENERATIVE
AI WILL CHANGE OUR LIVES. LEI:
ONE, IT IS ABOUT ACCELERATED
COMPUTE, A NEW FORM OF COMPUTE
THAT IS FAR MORE EFFICIENT AND
POWERFUL.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT EXISTING
PLAYERS, THEY ARE USING IT TO
SUPPORT THEIR CURRENT BUSINESS
MODEL.
IF YOU LOOK AT INFRASTRUCTURE
AS A SERVICE IN THE CLOUD, YOU
ARE SEEING THEIR SPENDING
BECAUSE HEY DAVE -- AWS IS
GROWING, GPC IS GOING.
IN SOME EXISTING INDUSTRIES,
WHETHER ADVERTISING OR LIFE
SCIENCE, AUTONOMOUS DRIVING,
FOR THAT MATTER, YOU ARE SEEING
GENERATIVE AI MAKE A POSITIVE
IMPACT ALREADY.
WE ACTUALLY BELIEVE THIS IS A
GREAT TIME FOR ACTIVE
INVESTING, BECAUSE THIS IS A
TIME YOU CAN USE IT TO IDENTIFY
THE FUTURE WINNERS AND LEADERS.
IT IS AN OPPORTUNITY WHEN
CENTER TRANSFORMATIVE PRODUCT
CYCLE HAPPENS.
YOU REDEFINE WHO ARE THE FUTURE
WINNERS AND LEADERS.
IT IS A ONCE-IN-A-LIFETIME
OPPORTUNITY FOR THESE PLAYERS
TO GET INTO EACH OTHER'S
BACKYARD.
WE ACTUALLY THINK YOU ARE GOING
TO SEE MORE AND MORE BUSINESS
MODEL EMERGING.
WE ALWAYS SAY SOMETHING TO TAKE
A STEP BACK.
WITHOUT THE BUILDUP OF THE
MOBILE ECOSYSTEM, WE WOULDN'T
HAVE UBER, SPOTIFY, FACEBOOK.
WE WOULDN'T HAVE THE SUBURBS IF
WE DIDN'T BUILD THE HIGHWAY.
IT IS STILL EARLY.
WE BELIEVE INFRASTRUCTURE
BUILDS ON ITSELF.
WE ARE WATCHING VERY CLOSELY
ACROSS INDUSTRIES TO SEE NEW
BUSINESS MODEL ACTUALLY
EMERGING. CAROLINE:
BUT WHAT IS SO INTERESTING, YOU
HAVE BEEN DOING THIS SINCE
1999, 2000.
MANY PEOPLE GO BACK TO CISCO IN
THOSE YEARS, AND ULTIMATELY HOW
FAR IT RAN OUT, AND THIS FOCUS
ON ONE PARTICULAR NAME, BUT
INDEED, THE ENTIRE TECH SECTOR.
IS THERE TOO MUCH FOCUS ON A
SINGLE OR NAME LIKE NVIDIA?
WHEN WE BROUGHT IT OUT?
WHEN DO WE NOT GET THE ULTIMATE
CRASH THAT WE SAW IN THE
1990'S, 2000S RUN-UP? LEI:
I AGREE, THE MARKET IS HYPER
FOCUSED ON ONE THING, BUT WE
ARE FOCUSED ON THE ENTIRE
ECOSYSTEM.
WE THINK THERE ARE A LOT OF
OPPORTUNITIES OUTSIDE.
YOU TAKE THE SUPPLY CHAIN, FOR
EXAMPLE.
IF YOU TAKE A STEP BACK AND
THINK AT A HIGH LEVEL, THERE IS
SUCH A-DEMAND IMBALANCE.
THE DEMAND -- THERE IS SUCH
SUPPLY-DEMAND IMBALANCE.
THE DEMAND REMAINS SO ROBUST
AND THERE ARE SUPPLY CHAIN
ISSUES.
THERE IS PRICING POWER AND
PROFIT POOLS.
WITH AI, WE ARE REDEFINING THE
FUTURE BUSINESS MODELS.
YOU CAN ACTUALLY FIND FUTURE
WINNERS AND LOSERS.
IT IS THE ACCELERATED COMPUTE,
THE IMPACT OF THE FUTURE OF
TECHNOLOGY, AND FRANKLY, THE
FUTURE OF ECONOMIC GROWTH. ED:
LEI, I TRIED TO SPEAKER JOHNSON
WRONG ABOUT THE ENERGY
COMPONENT ABOUT THE SUPPLY
CHAIN.
LET'S LISTEN TO WHAT HE SAID.
>> THE MOST IMPORTANT THING WE
DO IS INCREASE PERFORMANCE AND
EFFICIENCY OF THE NEXT
GENERATION.
BLACKWELL IS MANY TIMES MORE
PERFORMING THAN HOPPER AT THE
SAME LEVEL OF POWER USED.
THAT IS ENERGY EFFICIENCY.
MORE PERFORMANCE WITH THE SAME
AMOUNT OF POWER OR SAME
PERFORMANCE AT A LOWER POWER.
ED: JENSEN LOOKS AT THE ENERGY
COMPONENT THROUGH THE LENS OF
BLACKWELL'S GREATER EFFICIENCY.
HOW DO YOU LOOK AT THE ENERGY
COMPONENT OF ACCELERATED
COMPUTING? LEI:
WE CERTAINLY ARE VERY
CONSTRUCTIVE ON THE ENERGY
EFFICIENCY OF THE FUTURE OF
COMPUTE, BUT WE ALSO ARE
CONSTRUCTIVE ON THE PHYSICAL
INSTRUCTOR ASPECT OF IT.
WHEN WE LOOK AT HOW THE DATA
CENTERS WILL BE POWERED, SO
MUCH GREENFIELD POWER IS
ACTUALLY NEEDED.
WE ARE CONSTRUCTIVE ON THE
PHYSICAL ASPECT OF IT.
IF HE THINK ABOUT THE DIGITAL
INFRASTRUCTURE, IT AS
LEAPFROGGED THE PHYSICAL
INFRASTRUCTURE OF MANY
DEVELOPED NATIONS COME AND WE
FIND MANY INTERESTING PLAYS
THERE AS WELL. ED:
LEI, HOW DO YOU BALANCE ALL OF
THIS?
THE CHAOS AROUND NVIDIA
EARNINGS, ALL OF THE CENTRAL
BANK TO SPEAK, ALL OF THE
ECONOMIC DATA IN ONE WEEK?
WHAT WAS THAT LIKE FOR YOU AND
ALL THE THINGS QUESTION YOUR
DESK?
LE-- ALL THE THINGS CROSSING
YOUR DESK? LEI:
THAT IS THE EXCITEMENT OF BEING
IN INNOVATION INVESTOR.
WE FOCUS ON STORIES THAT DRIVE
THE STOCK FUNDAMENTALS WERE
GONE THIS OF WHAT THE CENTRAL
BANK WILL DO.
WE ALWAYS GO BACK TO IN 2008,
IPHONES STILL SOLD.
IRRESPECTIVE OF ECONOMIC CYCLE,
IF WE FOCUS ON FUNDAMENTALS,
THAT IS WHAT ACTIVE INVESTMENT
IS ABOUT.
WE FIND STORIES THAT WILL GROW
IRRESPECTIVE A CYCLICAL
BACKDROP. CAROLINE:
IF YOU ARE LOOKING ACTIVE AT
THE MOMENT AND YOU SEEK
VALUATION OF CERTAIN COMPANIES,
HOW DO YOU BROADEN THEN OUT,
LOOK AT THE SUPPLY-SIDE?
AM I AUTOMATICALLY THINK AND GO
GLOBAL HERE?
LOOK AT THE JAPANESE SUPPLIES
THAT FEED INTO NVIDIA.
HOW ARE YOU LOOKING AT THE
BROADER WEALTH OF OPPORTUNITIES
OUTSIDE THE MAG SEVEN NAMES?
LEI:
WE GO BACK TO THE FUNDAMENTALS.
WE ARE ACTIVE INVESTORS.
WE LOOK AT EACH COMPANY WITH
RESPECT TO ITS OWN GROWTH
OPPORTUNITY.
OBVIOUSLY AT A HIGH LEVEL WE
LOOK AT HOW BIG THE SECULAR
TREND IS. THEN WE LOOK AT THE
DEMAND-SUPPLY IMBALANCE AND THE
LONGEVITY OF IT.
THEN WE LOOK AT IT AT A GLOBAL
LEVEL AND FIND WHO ARE THE
FUTURE WINNERS AND LOSERS.
AGAIN, GO BACK TO GET IS A TIME
OF CHANGE, A TIME OF
INFLECTION, AND AT TIME OF
INFLECTION SOMETIMES YOU FIND
THE MARKET WILL UNDERESTIMATE
THE GROWTH OPPORTUNITIES OF
DIFFERENT PARTS OF THE SUPPLY
CHAIN COME AND THAT IS WHAT WE
FOCUS ON, ONE STOCK AT A TIME,
HOW STRONG THE GROWTH MOMENTUM
IS, AND MORE IMPORTANTLY, ARE
THEY GOING TO GET MAJORITY OF
THE FUTURE PROFIT POOL, HOW THE
INDUSTRY IS BEING RESHAPED.
THAT'S WHAT WE FOCUS ON.
CAROLINE:
YOU TALK ABOUT THIS HIGHWAY,
AND EVERYONE IS FOCUSED ON THE
INFRASTRUCTURE PLAY.
EVERYONE IS TRYING TO WORK OUT,
PARTICULARLY THE VC COMMUNITY,
WHERE THE VALUE IS IN THE
APPLICATIONS.
YOU TALK ABOUT HEALTH CARE AND
ADVERTISING ADOPTED GENERATIVE
AI.
WHERE ARE SOME OF THE LONG-TERM
OPPORTUNITIES?
WHERE HAS IT BEEN UNDERVALUED
AND UNDERAPPRECIATED WHERE IT
CAN ADOPT GENERATIVE AI? LEI:
AT A HIGH LEVEL I WOULD SAY WE
ARE STILL EARLY, AND BEING
INNOVATION INVESTORS, SOMETIMES
IT DOES REQUIRE A TOUCH OF
IMAGINATION, BECAUSE THE FUTURE
HAS YET TO COME.
THE FUTURE IS THE BEST PART OF
IT. I WOULD ALSO POINT TO WE ARE
ALREADY SEEING THIS TIME IS A
LITTLE BIT DIFFERENT.
IF DO LOOK BACK THE PAST 15
YEARS, IT IS ABOUT CONSUMER
ELECTRONICS.
YOU ARE SEEING THE KILLER APP.
WE CALL THEM THE KILLER APP
BECAUSE WE CAN TOUCH AND FEEL.
THAT SAID, THIS IS ABOUT THE
INVESTOR TO UPGRADE, SO IT IS
LESS OBVIOUS, BUT IT DOESN'T
MEAN THE OPPORTUNITY IS NOT AS
BIG.
WE LOOK FORWARD, WE CAN SEE THE
DIGITAL MANUFACTURING, WHERE WE
THINK ABOUT RESTORING, HOW MUCH
WE ARE GOING TO NEED ON THE
AUTOMATION SIDE, AND ALSO THE
FUTURE OF ROBOTICS.
THOSE ARE SOME OF THE AREAS
THAT WE THINK WE ARE GOING TO
SEE A LOT OF GREAT
OPPORTUNITIES AHEAD. CAROLINE:
LOVE HAVING YOU ON TO TALK US
ALL THROUGH YOUR THESIS.
CHIEF INVESTMENT OFFICER OF
INNERVATION EQUITIES AT
ALLIANCEBERNSTEIN.
COMING UP, A CLASH BETWEEN
BRAZIL AND ELON MUSK IS HEATING
UP AS THE COUNTRY THREATENS TO
BLOCK X THE NEXT 14 HOURS.
WHAT ARE YOU WATCHING, ED? ED:
EARNINGS EARNINGS STILL
HAPPENING.
THERE ARE OTHER NAMES, AND ONE
OF THEM IS DELL, AND DELL AS
PART OF THE AI STORY.
IT ASSEMBLES THE SERVERS THAT
GO INTO DATA CENTERS, AND THAT
HELPED IT WITH ITS EARNINGS
REPORT.
WHICH WE WILL GET MORE ON LATER
IN THE PROGRAM.
THIS IS "BLOOMBERG TECHNOLOGY."
ED: A WIN FOR ELON MUSK.
THERE HAS BEEN A DISMISSAL OF A
LAWSUIT CLAIMING HE PUMPED UP
THE PRICE OF THE DOGECOI INTO
AN $250 BILLION "PYRAMID
SCHEME."
INVESTORS WHO LOST THOUSANDS OF
DOLLARS INVESTING IN THE QUINN
BLAMED MUSK FOR --IN THE COIN
BLAMED MUSK FOR PROMOTING THE
COIN ON X.
A JUDGE DISMISSED CLAIMS THAT
MUSK'S STATEMENTS WERE
ASPIRATIONAL RATHER THAN
FACTUAL, AND NO REASONABLE
INVESTOR COULD RELY UPON THEM.
MEANWHILE, A CLASH IN BRAZIL
FOR ELON MUSK.
THE COUNTRY'S TOP JUSTICE IS
TAKING ON MUSK COMPANIES AS HE
BLOCKED STARLINK BANK ACCOUNTS
IN LINE AMERICA'S LARGEST
ECONOMY.
ELON CALLING FOR JUSTICE AND
OUTRIGHT CRIMINAL OF THE WORST
KIND. KURT WAGNER HAS THE JOB OF
JOINING US IN EXPLAINING WHAT
IS GOING ON. LET'S START THERE.
KURT, WHAT IS GOING ON?
>> THIS HAS BEEN ONGOING FOR A
WHILE NOW.
THIS JUDGE, AS YOU MENTIONED,
HAS BEEN TRYING TO GET X TODAY
ACTION AGAINST CERTAIN ACCOUNTS
ON THE PLATFORM, RIGHT-WING
ACCOUNTS, MISINFORMATION,
THINGS LIKE THAT.
ELON IS A SELF-PROCLAIMED
FREE-SPEECH ABSOLUTIST AND IS
SAYING WE ARE NOT GOING TO DO
THAT, WE ARE NOT GOING TO
REMOVE THESE ACCOUNTS OR ADHERE
TO YOUR DEMANDS.
AS A RESULT, HE A FEW WEEKS AGO
SHUT X'S OPERATIONS IN THE
COUNTRY.
NOW THE JUDGE IS SAYING YOU
NEED AT LEAST A LEGAL
REPRESENTATIVE HERE IN THE
COUNTRY IN ORDER TO OPERATE,
AND IF YOU DON'T APPOINT ONE,
WE WILL REMOVE THE APP ENTIRELY.
IT SOUNDS LIKE X IS NOT GOING
TO APPOINT SOMEONE, SO WE ARE
IN A BIT OF A STANDOUT WAITING
TO SEE IS THIS JUDGE IS GOING
TO FOLLOW THROUGH AND BAN X IN
BRAZIL. CAROLINE:
AND THIS IS WHERE ELON MUSK'S
CONGLOMERATE OF COMPANIES
SUDDENLY COMES TO BYTE HIM,
BECAUSE THIS JUDGE ISN'T TAKING
ACTION JUST AT X ALONE. KURT:
THAT'S RIGHT, THIS IS THE ELON,
INC., UNIVERSE.
TO GET TO X, THE JUDGE IS GOING
THROUGH STARLINK, ONE OF ELON'S
OTHER BUSINESSES.
FREEZING BANK ACCOUNTS THERE IN
ORDER TO TAKE MONEY FROM FINES
THAT X OWES.
TO YOUR POINT, CAROLINE, THIS
IS A GREAT EXAMPLE WHERE
RUNNING SIX DIFFERENT
COMPANIES, ESPECIALLY IN
COMPANIES WHERE THERE ARE
ADVERSARIAL RELATIONSHIPS, CAN
BE A DETRIMENT TO HIM.
THIS IS SOMETHING THAT WENT
ELON FIRST BOUGHT X WAS A REAL
CONCERN, WITH THEIR BE
GOVERNMENTS AROUND THE WORLD
THAT WOULD APPLY PRESSURE ON
TESLA OR STARLINK IT ORDER TO
GET TO THE SPEECH-RELATED
ISSUES THAT HAVE BEEN ON X.
WE ARE SEEING THAT PLAY OUT IN
BRAZIL. ED:
KURT, I KNOW THIS SOUNDS LIKE A
SIMPLE,, BASIC QUESTION BUT
WHAT IS X'S FOOTPRINT IN THE
COUNTRY OF BRAZIL?
WHAT ARE WE TALKING ABOUT
OPERATIONALLY? KURT:
OPERATIONALLY I BELIEVE IT WAS
SOMEWHAT SMALL COMPARED TO A
LOT OF WHERE THEY OPERATE IN
OTHER COUNTRIES, LIKE THE U.S.
OR EVEN IN JAPAN.
FROM A USER BASE PERSPECTIVE,
WE DON'T KNOW EXACTLY.
I'VE SEEN ESTIMATES BETWEEN 20
MILLION AND 40 MILLION ACTIVE
USERS THERE.
MY UNDERSTANDING IT IS AROUND
THE THIRD-LARGEST MARKET FOR
THEM FOR USER BASE BEHIND THE
UNITED STATES AND JAPAN.
SIGNIFICANT FOR SURE.
RESULT IS A COUNTRY WHERE
PEOPLE ARE VICTIMS BRAZIL IS A
COUNTRY WERE -- BRAZIL IS A
COUNTRY OR PEOPLE ARE ACTIVE
ONLINE, WHATSAPP IS HUGE THERE,
INSTAGRAM IS HUGE THERE.
THIS IS A SIGNIFICANT ISSUE FOR
THEM. I DON'T KNOW IF THE USER
TRANSLATES TO A HUGE REVENUE
DRIVER FOR THE COMPANY.
REGARDLESS, THE OPTICS AND
TAKING A COUNTRY OF SUCH
IMPORTANCE AND SIGNIFICANCE IN
THE WORLD, BUT CERTAINLY LATIN
AMERICA, OFF OF X ENTIRELY IS A
BIG DEAL IF THIS ENDS UP
HAPPENING. CAROLINE:
WE ARE USED TO ELON MUSK FIRING
OFF ON HIS OWN PLATFORM, BUT HE
HAS GOT SOME FIGHTING TALK FOR
THIS SUPREME COURT JUSTICE, IN
PARTICULAR SAYING THAT
ULTIMATELY HE IS AN OUTRIGHT
CRIMINAL OF THE WORST KIND
MASQUERADING AS A JUDGE.
WHAT SORT OF IMPLICATIONS IS
THIS GOING TO HAVE FOR ELON
MUSK TO SAY THAT SORT OF THING?
KURT:
WELL, IT IS HARD TO IMAGINE
THERE IS A BRIDGE BEING REBUILT
AT ANY POINT IN THE NEAR FUTURE.
HE'S GOING SCORCHED EARTH ON
THIS JUDGE.
HE POSTED AN IMAGE THAT WAS
GREETED BY GRO -- CREATED BY
GROK, IS AI BOT, THAT SHOWED
THE JUDGE BEHIND BARS, SAYING
YOU ARE GOING TO JAIL.
WHEN YOU HAVE SOMEONE LIKE ELON
WHO IS KNOWN TO LASH OUT AT HIS
COMPETITORS AND HAS ALMOST 200
MILLION FOLLOWERS ON X, THESE
ARE SERIOUS, SERIOUS ATTACKS.
WE'LL SEE WHAT IS GOING TO
HAPPEN, BUT I THINK THE BRIDGE
IS BURNT QUITE AGGRESSIVELY.
CAROLINE:
KURT WAGONER, APPRECIATE IT.
WE WILL BE THINKING ABOUT
ALIBABA NEXT. STAY TUNED.
THIS IS "BLOOMBERG TECHNOLOGY."
CAROLINE:
IT IS TIME NOW FOR "TALKING
TECH."
ALIBABA HAS WON THE ENDORSEMENT
OF CHINA'S ANTITRUST WATCHDOG.
ESTATE ADMINISTRATION FOR
MARKET REGULATION SAYING THE
COMPANY HAS CEASED TO THE
ANTI-COMPETITIVE PRACTICES.
THE MOVE SUGGESTS THAT BEIJING
IS KING TO SIGNAL SUPPORT FOR
THE INTERNET SECTOR.
CHINESE EV MAKERS ARE FEELING
THE IMPACT OF EU TARIFFS.
THEY ACCOUNTED FOR 9.9% OF EV
REGISTRATIONS IN EUROPE IN
JULY, DOWN FROM 10.2% IN JULY
2023.
AUTOMAKERS HAVE BEEN SCRAMBLING
TO ADJUST TO THE INTRODUCTION
OF NEW TARIFFS ON JULY 5 THAT
RAISED DUTIES ON CHINESE-MADE
EV'S.
UBER PLANNING TO EXPAND ITS
SOUTH KOREAN BUSINESS AND STEP
UP ITS BIT WITH A DOMESTIC
RIVAL.
THE CEO IS MAKING HIS FIRST
OFFICIAL BUSINESS TRIP TO THE
ASIAN NATION, SAYING THE
COMPANY IS MAKING HEADWAY IN
THE REGION AS RIDES JUMPED 8%
THE FIRST HALF OF 2024. ED:
COMING UP, NVIDIA IN TALKED
ABOUT JOINING IN OPENAI FUNDING
ROUND ALONG WITH APPLE AND
MICROSOFT.
IT'S TRANSFER DEADLINE DAY FOR
COPIES RAISING MONEY.
WE WILL HAVE THE DETAILS.
THIS IS "BLOOMBERG TECHNOLOGY."
>> NVIDIA, NOW ONE OF THE
WORLD'S MOST VALUABLE
COMPANIES, IMMERSED FROM AN
INDUSTRY OFTEN MISUNDERSTOOD.
GAMING.
THE FIRST MAJOR TRIUMPH IN 2001
WHEN BILL GATES -- THE CONSOLE
GAMING PLATFORM.
A VITAL STEPPINGSTONE THAT
ALIGNED NVIDIA HARDWARE WITH PC
BOUGHT BY GAMERS KEEN ON
UPGRADING COMPONENTS.
SOMETHING ELSE HAPPENED DURING
THOSE 20 YEARS.
PEOPLE STARTED TO ASK IF THESE
THINGS ARE SO GOOD TRANSPORTING
CODE, COULD IT WORK THE OTHER
WAY AROUND?
GPUS EXCEL AT SOMETHING,
DIVIDING A PROBLEM INTO SMALL
CALCULATIONS AND SOLVING THEM
QUICKLY.
>> A LOT OF TIME YOU SEE THERE
ARE RUNS BECAUSE THERE ARE A
LOT OF APPLICATIONS OUTSIDE OF
GAMING.
>> COMPANIES ACQUIRE GPU'S FOR
USE WITH ARTIFICIAL
INTELLIGENCE.
CHATGPT USES NVIDIA HARDWARE.
NVIDIA BECAME THE LEADER BY
ADVANCING TECHNOLOGY DESIGN FOR
GAMES BUT VALUABLE TO
INDUSTRIES.
THEY KNEW TO SUCCEED THEY
NEEDED GAMERS. ED:
BLOOMBERG ORIGINALS TAKING A
LOOK BACK AND HOW NVIDIA GAME
DOMINATED THE AI INDUSTRY.
CHECK OUT THE FULL VERSION AT
YOUTUBE OR BLOOMBERG.COM.
LET'S LOOK AT WHAT SHARES OF
NVIDIA HAVE BEEN DOING.
FIVE DAYS, WE ARE DOWN BY
AROUND 9%.
IT IS THE BIGGEST WEEKLY
DECLINE GOING BACK TO APRIL.
THAT IS THE KIND OF RESPONSE WE
HAD.
THE BAR WAS SO HIGH, A STOCK UP
150% YEAR-TO-DATE, ALMOST 1000%
FROM ITS 2022 BEAR MARKET I DO
NOT THINK I HAVE EXPERIENCED
ONE WEEK LIKE THIS BUT IT HAS
BEEN A RIDE, LET'S SAY THAT.
CAROLINE:
$300 BILLION WIPED OFF ALMOST
IN TERMS OF MARKET
CAPITALIZATION.
SOURCES TELLING BLOOMBERG THAT
NVIDIA IS IN TALKS TO JOIN A
FUNDING ROUND THAT WOULD VALUE
THE START ABOUT MORE THAN $100
BILLION. LET'S GET RIGHT TO IT.
WHY WOULD NVIDIA WANT TO TAKE A
STRATEGIC STAKE IN OPENAI?
>> IT IS NVIDIA, MICROSOFT AND
APPLE, THE THREE MOST VIABLE
TECHNOLOGY COMPANIES IN THE
WORLD.
THEY HAVE A VESTED INTEREST IN
THE SUCCESS OF OPENAI.
THE REASON NVIDIA HAS BEEN
SUCCESSFUL OVER THE LAST TWO
YEARS IT IS SELLING A TON OF
COMPONENTS THE GPU'S MENTIONED
TO COMPANIES LIKE OPENAI AND
OTHERS THAT ARE POWERING
FEATURES ON THE CLOUD LIKE
CHATGPT, ALEXA AND OTHER TYPES
OF AI SERVICES.
APPLE IS INTEGRATING CHATGPT
INTO THE IOS TEAM LATER THIS
YEAR. MICROSOFT ALMOST ENTIRE
STRATEGY IS RELIANT ON OPENAI.
THEY KNOW OPENAI IS IMPORTANT
TO THE PRODUCTS OF TODAY.
IT IS ALSO POSSIBLE LIKE IN THE
CASE OF APPLE THAT EVEN MORE
CRITICAL TO EXPAND INTO THEIR
ECOSYSTEMS. NOT ONLY DO THEY
HAVE A VESTED INTEREST, THEY
WANT SOME SKIN IN THE GAME.
THEY WANT TO BE AT THE TABLE.
TO DO THAT YOU HAVE TO PUT IN
$100 MILLION-PLUS. ED:
IT IS NOT STRAIGHTFORWARD.
$100 MILLION IS A DROP IN THE
OCEAN FOR NVIDIA BUT MY
UNDERSTANDING IS THEY WANT TO
KNOW WHAT IS GOING ON.
NOT SUGGESTING THEY GET A BOARD
SEAT AT THE TABLE BUT AT LEAST
THEY WOULD KNOW WHAT IS GOING
ON, BROADLY SPEAKING.
IT IS COMPLETELY DIFFERENT TO
APPLE.
THE APPLE SIDE OF THIS TO ME IS
THE BIGGER BIT.
WHAT IS YOUR UNDERSTANDING OF
APPLE'S MOTIVATIONS TO BE ON
THE CAP TABLE OF OPENAI? MARK:
APPLE WANTED A BOARD OBSERVER
SEAT.
THEY LITERALLY WANTED TO BE AT
THE TABLE.
THEY ONE OF SAME ACCESS
MICROSOFT HAD DESPITE A LOT
LESS MONEY INVESTED.
FOR VARIOUS REASONS, OPENAI
PULLED OUT OF THAT BOARD
OBSERVER SITUATION WITH BOTH
MICROSOFT AND APPLE LAST MONTH
IN JULY.
RIGHT AFTER AGREEING TO THE
APPLE BOARD OBSERVER SEAT, SO
THAT FELL APART.
THE NEXT BEST WAY TO BE
INVOLVED AND HAVE A SEAT AT THE
FIGURATIVE TABLE IS TO JOIN THE
CAP TABLE AND BE AN INVESTOR.
IT IS IMPORTANT TO THE NEW
VERSION OF IPHONE AND IOS GIVEN
IT WILL BE PART OF THE NEW AI
SERVICES.
OVER TIME, APPLE'S INTERNAL AI
STRATEGY IS KIND OF WEAK.
IF THEY DO NOT GET UP TO SNUFF
THEY WILL HAVE TO MAKE A
DECISION TO PARTNER WITH SOME
SORT OF TEAM WITH JENNIFER OF
AI ORGANIZATION AND THERE IS NO
BETTER PARTNER AT THIS POINT IN
OPENAI.
BY BEING INVOLVED THEY GIVE
THEMSELVES OPTIONS FOR THE
FUTURE BUT ALSO HAVE A BETTER
UNDERSTANDING OF WHAT IS GOING
ON FOR A CURRENT PARTNER.
CAROLINE:
ONCE AGAIN, ITS INTEGRAL LARGE
LANGUAGE MODEL MAKERS AT THE
SAME BIG TECH COMPANIES.
THEY CANNOT LIKE THIS. MARK:
I AM SURE THEY DO NOT LIKE IT.
AT THIS POINT, THE ONLY THING
THEY CAN DO IS TRY TO STOP IT.
WE HAVE NOT SEEN ANY --
EVIDENCE THEY WILL TRY TO PULL
THIS APART.
IT IS UNCLEAR IF OPENAI IS
BLOCKING INVESTMENTS FROM OTHER
COMPANIES SO WE HAVE TO SEE HOW
OPEN THIS IS.
I THINK REGULATORS WILL WAIT
AND SEE WHAT THE FINAL NUMBERS
ARE. THIS IS ALL FLUID.
THERE IS A POSSIBILITY
MICROSOFT, APPLE AND NVIDIA ARE
NOT PART OF THIS.
THAT IS EXTRAORDINARILY
UNLIKELY.
WE ARE A COUPLE WEEKS TOO EARLY
FOR REGULATORS TO START
CREATING PROBLEMS FOR THESE
INVESTMENTS.
IF THEY DO MOVE THROUGH, YOU
CAN BE CERTAIN THEY WILL. ED:
I DO NOT THINK IT IS THE END OF
THE STORY.
MARK GURMAN, THANK YOU VERY
MUCH.
COMING UP, MCAFEE LAUNCHING THE
WORLD'S FIRST DEEPFAKE DETECTOR.
WE WILL DISCUSS WITH THE CTO
NEXT.
MORE EARNINGS, MORE MOVERS,
WHAT IS GOING ON? CAROLINE:
MORE THAN 15% HIGHER EARNINGS.
THE DATABASE SOFTWARE COMPANY
IS STRONG FOR THE SECOND
QUARTER RESULTS, BEATING
EXPECTATIONS.
SOME ANALYSTS CITIES ARE
ENCOURAGING RESULTS.
NOT ALL IS PERFECT WITH THE
OVERALL GROWTH RATES HAVE COME
DOWN.
THIS IS "BLOOMBERG TECHNOLOGY."
♪
ED: LET'S GET A CHECK ON THE
MARKETS. BITCOIN.
FOR EVERYTHING THAT HAS BEEN
GOING ON, TAKE A LOOK AT THE
LAST FIVE DAYS.
WE ARE BELOW $60,000 PER TOKEN.
THERE WAS A PERIOD WHERE IT WAS
SLIGHTLY DOWN.
IT HAS BEEN BEHAVING LIKE A
RISK ASSET IN LINE WITH
EVERYTHING ELSE GOING ON.
THERE IS SOME POLITICAL
ADJACENT HEADLINE THAT MIGHT BE
AFFECTING IT.
I DO NOT KNOW BECAUSE I HAVE
BEEN QUITE BUSY WITH THE OTHER
STUFF BUT THAT IS THE HEADLINE
I SEE ON THE BLOOMBERG TERMINAL.
CAROLINE:
THIS IS SUPPLY AND DEMAND
DYNAMICS WHEN IT COMES TO
CRYPTO AND BITCOIN IN
PARTICULAR.
HOW MUCH BITCOIN -- SONALI:
MANY OF THESE GOVERNMENT SEIZED
BITCOIN LOOKING FOR CRIMINAL
ACTIVITY.
THE NUMBERS ARE QUITE LARGE.
THE U.S.
ADMINISTRATION HOLDS MORE THAN
200,000.
UKRAINE HOLD SOME AS WELL.
DONATIONS TO FINANCE THEIR PART
IN THE WAR.
WHEN YOU LOOK AT WHAT IS GOING
ON, A LOT OF THIS IS WRITTEN
ABOUT THE SUPPLY ISSUE, THAT
OVERHANG TO THE TUNE OF $33
BILLION.
FOR THE PEOPLE WHO BOUGHT IT
DURING AUGUST, THAT HAS BEEN
PRETTY FRUSTRATING.
YOU SAW A BIG BUMP IN BITCOIN
PRICES AT THE HEELS OF THAT
POWERFUL P -- POWELL PIVOT BUT
YOU HAVE SEEN ALMOST ALL OF IT
ERASED AFTER THE BUMP.
$56,000 TO $65,000.
THE OTHER BRIGHT SPOT IS FIN
TRADING VALUES.
ALONG WITH THE BITCOIN ETF
MARKETS. ACCORDING TO BLOOMBERG
INTELLIGENCE, YOU HAVE SEEN AS
HIGH AS $10 BILLION IN
LIQUIDITY AND NOW CLOSER TO $1
BILLION.
THINGS COULD BE DIFFERENT ONCE
WE GET PAST THE SUMMER SLUMP
BUT IT HAS BEEN AN ORDERLY
MOVEMENT THIS MONTH, EVEN IF
BITCOIN HAS NOT KEPT UP WITH
THE BROADER MARKET. ED:
THE POLITICS ADJACENT SIDE OF
BITCOIN I WAS REFERRING TO WAS
FORMER PRESIDENT TRUMP AND MAKE
BITCOIN GREAT AGAIN.
THE QUOTE IS HE WANTED BITCOIN
TO BE MADE IN THE UNITED STATES.
AHEAD OF THE ELECTION, THAT IS
A FACTOR. SONALI:
IT CERTAINLY IS.
WHEN IT COMES TO BITCOIN
MINING, A LOT OF THAT IS DONE
BASED OUT OF CHINA.
SHANGHAI AND BEIJING-BASED
FIRMS THAT ARE MUCH BIGGER IN
THE BITCOIN MINING SPACE THAN
WHAT YOU SEE IN THE U.S.
THERE IS A SERVICE YOU HAVE
SEEN SOME MOVEMENT TOWARD IN
RECENT DAYS BUT THERE IS A LONG
WAY TO CATCH UP AND A LOT OF
ENERGY NEEDS TO HELP THAT CATCH
UP HAPPEN.
NEXT WEEK WE WILL BE TACKLING
THIS ISSUE AT 12:00 P.M.
ON TUESDAY BECAUSE HOW HARD IS
IT TO MAKE THE MOVEMENT TO
U.S.-BASED FIRMS?
WE WILL ASK OUR GUESTS ABOUT
HOW THEY FEEL.
WE DO NOT HAVE A LOT OF
INFORMATION FROM KAMALA HARRIS
ON HOW SHE MIGHT APPROACH
CRYPTO.
PEOPLE HAVE BEEN FRUSTRATED
WITH THE FCC UNDER THE BIDEN
ADMINISTRATION.
YOU HAVE HAD BITCOIN REACHED
RECORD HIGHS UNDER BIDEN AND
MULTIPLE ETF'S APPROVED.
IT IS HARD TO SAY AT THE END OF
THE DAY. THEY JUST WANT CLARITY.
IT SHOULD SEEM LIKE WE WILL GET
MORE CLARITY IN THE COMING
MONTHS. ED:
SONALI BASAK, HAPPY FRIDAY.
THANK YOU VERY MUCH.
COMPUTER SECURITY COMPANY
MCAFEE HAS RECENTLY ANNOUNCED A
NEW TOOL THAT WILL HELP USERS
FIGURE OUT IF THE AUDIO THEY
ARE LISTENING TO IN A VIDEO IS
REAL OR A DEEPFAKE.
IT COMES AT A PIVOTAL TIME.
WE ARE AROUND TWO MONTHS FROM
THE U.S. PRESIDENTIAL ELECTION.
EARLIER THIS YEAR WE SAW A SCAM
THAT IMPERSONATED PRESIDENT
BIDEN URGING VOTERS IN NEW
HAMPSHIRE TO SKIP VOTING IN THE
PRIMARIES.
STEVE GROBMAN IS CTO AT MCAFEE.
I WANT TO START BY ASKING YOU,
WHY THE TWO WILL NOW?
WHY DID YOU NOT DO THIS SOONER?
STEVE: THANK YOU FOR HAVING ME.
WE ARE AT A PACE AT MCAFEE AND
THE INDUSTRY WHERE WE NOW HAVE
THE POWER TO BUILD THIS KIND OF
TECHNOLOGY TOOL AND MAKE IT
PRACTICAL FOR CONSUMERS.
PART OF THAT IS WHAT WE HAVE
DEVELOPED.
THERE IS A RAPID INVESTMENT AT
MCAFEE BUT ALSO NEW TECHNOLOGY
IN THE INDUSTRY.
FOR EXAMPLE, MCAFEE DEEPFAKE
DETECTOR THAT WE LAUNCHED LAST
WEEK, IT TAKES FULL ADVANTAGE
OF THE NARROW PROCESSORS IN THE
LATEST GENERATION OF AI PCS.
IT IS THAT HARDWARE-SOFTWARE
COMBINATION THAT MAKES THIS
PRACTICAL SO USERS CAN RUN THE
ANALYSIS ON THE AUDIO, LOOKING
FOR WHETHER SOMETHING IS REAL
OR FAKE CONTINUOUSLY WITHOUT
IMPACTING OUR PERFORMANCE. ED:
OK.
THERE ARE SOME CONSTRAINTS ON
THE ROLLOUT OF THIS.
I JUST WANT TO SAY, AGAIN, IS
ANALYSIS OF THE AUDIO IN A
VIDEO.
IT TOOK ME A WHILE TO GET MY
HEAD AROUND THAT.
WHY IS THAT APPROACH IMPORTANT?
AN AUDIO REVIEW ON A VIDEO?
STEVE:
WE LOOKED AT THIS CLOSELY WOULD
WE STARTED OUR RESEARCH INTO
DEEPFAKES AND ONE THING WE
FOUND WAS ALMOST EVERY FAKE
VIDEO HAS FAKE AUDIO.
OFTEN THERE IS NO FAKE VIDEO
ELEMENT OF IT.
SOMETIMES IT IS GOING TO B
ROLL, SOMETIMES IT IS USING
REAL VIDEO OF SOMEONE AND
HAVING FAKE AUDIO.
BY CHECKING AUDIO FIRST, WE ARE
ABLE TO COVER THE MOST SCAMS
AND DISINFORMATION THAT IS
HARMFUL TO CONSUMERS.
WE KNOW THAT DEEPFAKE AUDIO IS
USED FOR ALL SORTS OF PURPOSES,
SOME OF IT NOT HARMFUL.
THERE IS A LOT OF AI PARODY
VIDEOS OUT THERE, THAT IS FINE.
WHAT WE ARE TRAINED TO HELP
CONSUMERS DETECT IS WHEN THEY
ARE LOOKING AT SOMETHING LIKE
AN INVESTMENT SCAM THAT HAS A
CELEBRITY OR WELL-KNOWN
INDIVIDUAL MAKING STATEMENTS
AND IT IS THAT DEEPFAKE AUDIO
THAT THEY CAN THEN DETECT.
THAT IS GENERATED BY AI.
YOU HAVE TO BE A BIT MORE
CAREFUL.
ESPECIALLY AS WE ARE TWO MONTHS
AWAY FROM THE U.S.
ELECTION, ANYTHING WE CAN HELP
TO ARM CONSUMERS WITH POWERFUL
TOOLS TO DETECT DISINFORMATION
IS SUPER HELPFUL. CAROLINE:
IT IS REALLY QUITE INTERESTING,
ALMOST FUN, GOING ON TO YOUR
WEBSITE AND SEEING -- TAYLOR
SWIFT WILL NOT SEND YOU A FREE
DUTCH OVEN.
IT SHOWS A LOT OF B ROLL.
GWYNETH PALTROW FOR EXAMPLE.
GOING BACK TO WHAT ED SAID
ABOUT LIMITATIONS, HOW CAN WE
BROADEN THIS OUT.
STEVE:
THIS IS OUR INITIAL LAUNCH.
ONE THING YOU WILL SEE FROM
MCAFEE IS THIS IS THE FIRST
INNING AND ALONG GIVEN WE ARE
NOT STOPPING.
WE HAVE A LOT OF GREAT
TECHNOLOGY IN THE PIPELINE
LOOKING AT ALL SORTS OF OTHER
ELEMENTS AROUND HELPING
CONSUMERS DETECT AI GENERATED
CONTENT.
WE ANNOUNCED SOME PARTNERSHIPS
WITH INTEL A FEW MONTHS AGO AND
YOU WILL SEE SOME GREAT THINGS
FROM US IN THE FUTURE.
WHILE WE ARE SUPER EXCITED
ABOUT WHAT WE LAUNCHED THIS
WEEK, IT IS REAL PRODUCT WE CAN
GET IN THE HANDS OF CONSUMERS.
TO SOLVE A REAL DIFFICULT
PROBLEM, THERE IS A LOT TO COME.
CAROLINE:
WE HAVE AN AUDIENCE THAT LOVES
THE NITTY-GRITTY OF THE PROBLEM.
HOW DIFFICULT IS IT?
WHAT TECHNOLOGY HAVE YOU USED
YOURSELVES TO UNCOVER THESE
DEEPFAKES? STEVE:
IT IS A DIFFICULT PROBLEM.
ONE REASON I AM SO PROUD OF THE
TECHNOLOGISTS AND THE DATA
SCIENTISTS WE HAVE AT MCAFEE IS
WE INVENTED A LOT OF NEW
TECHNOLOGY BUT WE ALSO WORK
WITH OUR HARDWARE PARTNERS, THE
GREAT FOLKS AT QUALCOMM AND
INTEL HAVE BEEN WORKING WITH US
FOR MONTHS.
WE HAVE BEEN WORKING WITH OUR
OS PARTNERS, MICROSOFT, AND WE
BUILD NEW AI ALGORITHMS THAT
ARE BASICALLY DETECTING AI
GENERATED CONTENT.
YOU CAN ALSO THINK OF IT AS WE
ARE BUILDING GOOD AI TO DETECT
AI GENERATED CONTENT THAT COULD
BE HARMFUL TO CONSUMERS AND
REALLY GIVING THEM THE TOOLS
THAT THEY CAN USE IN
CONJUNCTION WITH A BETTER
EDUCATION OF UNDERSTANDING THAT
THREATS AND SCAMS CAN BE AI
GENERATED, TO PROTECT
THEMSELVES.
ONE WAY WE ARE DOING THAT IS IN
CONJUNCTION WITH THE LAUNCH, WE
ARE ALSO LAUNCHING AN AI HUB,
WHICH IS A WEBSITE THAT FOCUSES
ON THE EDUCATION SIDE.
IT IS A COMBINATION OF
TECHNOLOGY AND EDUCATING THE
GENERAL PUBLIC TO KEEP
THEMSELVES SAFE FROM THIS NEW
WAVE OF CYBERCRIME THAT CAN BE
REALLY DAMAGING.
WE HAVE SEEN SOME OF THE AI
SCAMS THAT CAN TAKE ANYWHERE
FROM $250 TO $500,000. ED:
WHEN I WAS A KID I HAD MCAFEE
ON MY PERSONAL COMPUTER.
IN THIS DAY AND AGE -- SORRY
FOR THIS WASHY STATEMENT --
WHAT IS THE BUSINESS MODEL FOR
YOU GUYS IN TRYING TO FIGHT
DEEPFAKES IN AN ELECTION CYCLE?
STEVE:
MCAFEE IS COMMITTED TO KEEPING
CONSUMERS SAFE FROM DIGITAL
THREATS AND THAT MEANS ALL
SORTS OF DIGITAL THREATS.
THE CLASSIC DIGITAL THREATS
WITH MALWARE, DANGEROUS
WEBSITES, WE ARE STILL HEAVILY
INVESTED IN THAT AND THAT IS A
BIG PART OF OUR BUSINESS BUT WE
KNOW KEEPING CONSUMERS SAFE IS
MUCH MORE.
PROTECTING CONSUMERS FROM
DISINFORMATION, SCAMS, HELPING
THEM PROTECT THEIR IDENTITY AND
ALL OF THE THINGS THAT WILL BE
THE FORWARD-LOOKING CHALLENGES
FOR CONSUMERS IN 2024 AND
BEYOND. CAROLINE:
STEVE GROBMAN, GREAT TO SPEAK
WITH YOU. CTO OF MCAFEE.
DELL GETTING A BOOST FROM ITS
AI SERVERS.
WE WILL UNPACK THE RESULTS NEXT.
ED: DELL DELIVERING
BETTER-THAN-EXPECTED EARNINGS.
SECOND QUARTER REVENUE JUMPING
9% DUE TO AN INCREASE IN SALES
OF SERVERS THAT HANDLE AI
WORKLOADS.
IT IS THE AI OPTIMIZE SERVER.
WHAT I'M TRYING TO UNDERSTAND
WITH DELL, IS THIS BECAUSE THEY
ARE AN ESSENTIAL COG OR IS
THERE A VALUE ADD THAT THEY
BRING?
>> THERE IS A VALUE ADD THAT
DELL OFFERS THAT OTHERS HAVE A
TOUGH TIME DOING.
IF YOU THINK ABOUT HOW SOME OF
THESE ARE BUILDING UP, THEY ARE
BUILDING UP CLUSTERS OF AI
SERVERS.
WERE NOT TALKING ABOUT ONE
PARTICULAR SERVER BUT HUNDREDS
OF SERVERS.
CASE IN POINT, THEY DID $3.1
BILLION IN AI SERVER SALES.
THERE IS ONLY ONE OTHER COMPANY
I KNOW OF THAT EXCEEDED THAT.
CAROLINE:
SUPERMICRO HAS SOME ISSUES AT
THE MOMENT.
I AM INTERESTED IN THE
PROFITABILITY OF THIS.
REVENUE GOES HIGH AND THEY ARE
SELLING EXPENSIVE EQUIPMENT BUT
HOW MUCH ARE THEY GETTING IN
RETURN?
>> THAT IS A FANTASTIC QUESTION.
THERE WAS CONCERN ABOUT THE
MARGIN PROFILE OF AI SERVERS.
I WANT TO DISPEL THE MYTH IT IS
A ZERO MARGIN BUSINESS.
IT IS A LOW-MARGIN BUSINESS.
IT IS PROBABLY IN THE SINGLE
DIGITS.
IF WE SAW THE ISG MARGIN, THAT
IMPROVES SEQUENTIALLY.
PART OF IT IS THE CUSTOMER BASE.
THERE WAS SOME PRUDENCE IN
TERMS OF DEALMAKING FOR DELL.
CAROLINE:
WE WILL KEEP AN EYE ON DELL
RISING AFTER WHAT HAS BEEN A
REVENUE JUMP OF PROFITABILITY'S.
WE THANK YOU SO MUCH.
THAT IS THE END OF THIS EDITION
OF "BLOOMBERG TECHNOLOGY."
WHAT A WEEK.
WHAT A POWERFUL SET OF
INTERVIEWS YOU HAVE DONE. ED:
I HAVE A QUESTION STILL WHETHER
HE NEEDS MICHAEL DELL MORE THAN
THE OTHER WAY.
WE WILL CONTINUE TO LOOK INTO
THAT.
ASTONISHING ACROSS THE WORLD OF
TECHNOLOGY.
RECAP TODAY ON THE PODCAST ON
THE BLOOMBERG TERMINAL AND
ONLINE AT APPLE, SPOTIFY AND I
HEART.
THANK YOU TO THE TEAM IN NEW
YORK. WHAT A WEEK.